YOUSEF ALSAADANY

PHP BACKEND DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+201148286749

yousefalsaadany5@gmail.com

linkedin

<u>GitHub</u>

Egypt - Mansoura

SKILLS

Fundamentals: How Os Works - How Internet Works - Web Protocols Simple-knowledge: HTML - CSS -JavaScript - Bootstrap

Back-end: PHP - OOP - MYSQL - Laravel - Rest APIs

Advanced-skills: DRY, Kiss, Yagni & Solid Principles - Design Patterns - Clean Code - MVC - HMVC - Web Security - Web Scraping - Packages Development

Database-design: ERD - Transactions - ACID - N plus one problem- Rest APIs

Laravel-Packages: JWT - DOMPDF - Fast excel- Laravel Excel - Laravel Modules

EDUCATION

Management Information System In Delta Academy

COURSES

- Front-end Development
- CS50X, CS50T
- CompTIA A+
- OS Architecture
- Network Fundamentals
- Databases Design
- Back-end Development

PROFILE

I Have Started My Journey Since Late 2019, I Have A Passion For Most Aspects Of Computer Related Departments As I Dealt With Many Programming Languages And I am Currently Working As A Backend Developer Using PHP With 2 Years Experience Using PHP And 1 Year In Laravel Framework

WORK EXPERIENCE

Laravel Backend Developer

Forsa Platform 12/2022

 This Is An Educational Platform For Training Courses, Professional Courses, And Workshops That My Friend And I Developed, As It Helps Students And Graduates To Easily Find Jobs.

Laravel Backend Developer

Code Icons Company

03/2022 - Present

- Pilgrims Management Web App System, I Participated In Making A Large Part Of The APIs: link.
- Create An ERP System To Manage Schools And Educational Centers With Laravel. I Have Been Involved In Making A Large Part Of The APIs And Searching For Vulnerabilities In The Site.
- An e-commerce was made to sell clothes. I made APIs for use in the web and mobile by using Laravel: website link play store link.

Team Leader

Delta Academy

01/2022

 Where I managed more than one graduation project team during my studies at Delta Academy.

Laravel Backend Developer

Freelance

09/2022 - 10/2022

• I co-created a web application for publishing home auctions with Laravel : link

Instructor Backend Developer

Royal Academy Company

10/2022 - Present



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Laravel Package

Its function is to deal with site requests. It will give you the IP address of the
person who visited the site, his city, the page he visited, and the type of his
operating system in order to use it in making site analyzes such as knowing the
countries used for your site, and it will send an alert to your email to take the
appropriate action:

Cyber Technology (first laravel project)

• first project using laravel This is a site for a programming company with the use of the crud: <u>link</u>

Simple Blogger

• Simple Blogger U Can Add, Delete And Search Some Articles With Images : link

Search Engine (PHP)

• This is a simple search engine that was made using the TCP protocol. This search engine was designed using PHP, where the search engine communicates with the server through the server's IP and port, and the request is sent from the search engine to the server, so the server checks the request in the DNS and then sends accordingly response: github

INTERESTS

- Web Development
- Penetration Testing

REFRENCE

• Refrences are available upon request